Well, hello, we are here now, after we confirmed that the stone hasn't come out of the board's boundaries.
طيب هلا نحن هون بعد ما انه نحن تاكدنا انه الحجر ما طلع برات حدود اللعبه
And we confirmed that it's not in the starting area. Hello, we are here now, we are ready to move.
وتاكدنا انه هو مش بمنطقه البدايه فنحن هلا هون صرنا جاهزين للتحريك.
Well, hello, just like you saw in the video, we have rules for moving. Hello, we are the first check, so we need to check what? What do we need to check?
طيب هلا مثل ما شفتوا بالفيديو في عندنا قواعد للتحريك. هلا نحن اول تشيك يعني بدنا نشيكها هي شو؟
It's that we see the new position we want to go to, is it captured? Okay? What did we say the capture is?
هي انه نشوف البوزيشن الجديد اللي بدنا نروح عليه، في قلعه؟ تمام؟ القلعه شو قلنا هي؟
It's that it refers to a group of stones, it could be his? It could be the opponent's, so we need to check if this capture exists at all, the first thing.
هي عباره عن انه مجموعه احجار، ممكن تكون لي؟ ممكن تكون للخصم، فنحن بحاجه نشيك اذا هذه القلعه اساسا اول شيء موجوده.
Meaning, by default, in the position we want to go to, we need to see if there is a capture? Okay? If there is a capture, then we finish with it.
يعني بالبوزيشن فرضا تسعه اللي بدنا نروح عليه، بدنا نشوف في قلعه؟ تمام؟ اذا في قلعه خلص، بنشوف بنعالجها.
If there isn't a second capture. Well, let's assume there is a capture. Well, but I confirmed that there is a capture, so I must know whose capture it is.
اذا ما في قلعه حكي ثاني. طيب رح نعتبر انه في قلعه. طيب بس انا تاكدت انه في قلعه لازم لازم اعرف لمين هي القلعه.
Well, how do I know? Through this function. This function tells me, let's see it, what does it tell me?
طيب كيف بدي اعرف؟ من خلال التابع هذا. هذا التابع بيعرفني، تعال نشوفه، بيعرفني شو؟
It tells me whether this capture we are going to is his or the opponent's? Okay? By this logic.
انه هذه القلعه اللي انا هلا رايح عليها هي لي ولا ولا للخصم؟ تمام؟ بالمنطق هذا
Okay? I see the owner of the stone. If the capture we are going to was not there before, then...
تمام؟ بشوف الحجر مين المالك تبعه. ااا اذا القلعه اللي رايح عليها كان فيها حجر ما بيعود لي
The implication of the lock is for the opponent. So if this condition is met, and the lock that was passed over has no stone, it means I'm telling him that this lock is not for you.
فمعناتها القلعه هي للخصم. فهون اذا تحقق هالشرط وكانت القلعه اللي رايح عليها ما فيها ولا حجر لي، معناتها انا بقول له انه هي القلعه مش لك.
Okay? Simply, in the video, what did we see? But essentially, we are attacking a lock, and our stone is returned to the starting point.
تمام؟ ااا فانا بكل بساطه نحن بالفيديو شو شفنا؟ بس انه نحن نهجم على قلعه شخص، فنحن الحجر من احجار الخصم بيرجعوا لنقطه البدايه.
And my stone is also returned to the starting point. This is the logic we implemented. We told him, the token balance here is what I chose, reset.
وحجري كمان بيرجع لنقطه البدايه. هذا المنطق اللي عملناه. قلنا له التوزن توكن هذا اللي انا اخترته، ريسيت.
What does reset do? It returns it to the position minus one. It makes it so that it becomes minus one.
شو الريسيت بيعمل؟ بيرجعه للبوزيشن اللي بيساوي ناقص واحد. بيخليه انه هو صار ناقص واحد.
Of course, this value is still visible. Okay? And it makes the stone I just assumed here the first stone of this lock.
طبعا هذه القيمه لسه بنشوفها. تمام؟ وبيخلي حجر انا هون فرضته هو اول حجر بهذه القلعه
We return it again to the starting point. So what? In short, am I going to move my stone?
نرجعه كمان لل للمنطقه البدايه. يعني شو؟ يعني باختصار انا هلا بدي احرك الحجر تبعي.
I verified that it's not at the starting point and verified that it hasn't exceeded the array boundaries. Or that the game boundaries haven't been exceeded.
تاكدت انه مش بنقطه البدايه وتاكدت انه ما خلصت حدود المصفوفه. او مش المصفوفه حدود اللعبه.
I'm going to move it, so in new position, this new position will be checked.
انا هلا راح احركه، ففي نيو بوزيشن، هذا النيو بوزيشن راح شيك فيه.
I'll check if it's in a lock? If it's in a lock, I must check which lock? Okay? I must check whose lock it is?
راح اشوف هو في قلعه؟ اذا في قلعه لازم اشوف هالقلعه لمين؟ تمام؟ لازم اشوف القلعه لي ولا لعدوي؟
If it's the opponent's or the opponent's, meaning I'm going to return the stone that I
اذا لعدوي او لخصمي يعني ااا راح ارجع الحجر اللي انا
He placed this castle or assigned its location to the starting point. A random stone I chose here is the zero, meaning the first
قربته على هذه القلعه او حطيته مكان القلعه لما نقطه البدايه. وحجر عشوائي انا هون اخترته هو الصفر، يعني اول
AAA stone, returning to the starting point. Okay? Let's clarify. So if it wasn't for the enemy, but for me or my opponent, it was for me.
ااا حجر، رجعه كمان لنقطه البدايه. تمام؟ خالصين. طيب في حال هي ما كانت لعدوي، كانت لي او لخصمي، كانت لي.
Then, simply put, I add the stone that I moved to the castle.
فانا بكل بساطه بضيف الحجر اللي انا حركته للقلعه.
Alright, okay? How can I add the stone that belongs to the castle? This dependency takes a token which is a stone, an object from the Token class.
ليلي، تمام؟ طيب كيف يعني بضيف الحجر اللي لي للقلعه؟ هيك التابع هذا بياخذ منه توكن هو حجر، هو اوبجيكت من الكلاس توكن.
And adds it to the tokens specific to the castle. Here, you can keep watching as I move through the classes, this blue class is where I am.
وبضيفه للتوكنز اللي خاصين بالقلعه. هون بتكونوا انتم تضلوا تراقبوا فوق وين انا عم بتحرك بالكلاسات، هذا الكلاس الازرق هو انا اللي فيه هلا.
We just ensure that the castle that is going there belongs to me, I added the stone to this castle.
فنحن بس تاكدنا انه القلعه اللي رايح عليها هي لي، انا ضفت الحجر لهالقلعه.
Simply put, by flipping each token, which is each stone we have, a boolean value is set, indicating whether it has been placed or not.
بكل بساطه، وبقلب كل توكن بقلب كل حجر في عندنا نحن قيمه بولين هي از انكسد، يعني اذا هذا الحجر بقلعه او لا.
So I added it to the castle, I must leave it there so that I can know in the future whether this stone is placed or not.
فانا بس ضفته للقلعه لازم خليها ترو مشان اعرف انا مستقبلا انه هذا الحجر هو بقلعه او مش بقلعه.
Okay? So these conditions, if we said it was in a castle.
تمام؟ طيب هذه الاف اذا كان قلنا انه كان في قلعه.
So it is on the castle, okay? I don't want to continue. Then, if it wasn't in a castle, what does it mean?
يعني رايح على قلعه، تمام؟ ما بدي اضل اعيد. بعدين اذا ما كان في قلعه، شو معناتها؟
I'm going to move me onto an empty space. Okay? Meaning there's no castle. So, what if there's no castle?
راح اروح انا على مكان فاضي. ماشي؟ يعني ما في قلعه. طيب هلا اذا ما في قلعه
So you've been saying "castle" 1000 times, if there's no castle, what could it be? It could be a rock for my enemy.
يعني صرت قايل قلعه شيء 1000 مره، اذا ما في قلعه شو ممكن يكون في؟ ممكن يكون في يا حجر لعدوي
Or for my opponent, or maybe there's a rock for me. Okay? So, what am I going to do here?
او لخصمي او راح يكون في حجر لي. تمام؟ طيب انا هون شو راح اعمل؟
I'll do it again now, wrap around the players who are the two of us in our situation. Okay? And check if there's a rock for him in the space I'm going to.
راح اعمل كمان فور، لف على البلايرز اللي هن اثنين بحالتنا. تمام؟ وشوف اذا في حجر له بالمكان اللي انا رايح عليه ولا لا.
If there is a rock for him, then I'll return his rock to the initial position, meaning I'll set his position minus one.
اذا في له حجر، فانا برجع له حجره لمكان النقطه البدايه، يعني بخلي له البوزيشن ناقص واحد.
And move his rock. Okay? How do I move his rock? Using the function called move. Okay? So, let's go back to that move.
وبحرك حجري. تمام؟ كيف بحرك حجري؟ بالفانكشن اللي اسمها موف. تمام؟ طيب هلا بنرجع لهذه الموف.
So, in case I do this again after moving and I discover that I moved onto a space that has a rock for him, meaning it's not for him, it's for me.
طيب في حال انا كمان بعد ما حركت اكتشفت انه انا حركت على مكان في له حجر، يعني مش في له، في لي.
There's a rock for me, so I have to create a castle, right? So, how do I create a castle? Create Castle, follow with its name Create Castle.
انا حجر في، فلازم اعمل قلعه، صح؟ طيب كيف بعمل قلعه؟ كرييت كاسل، تابع اسمه كرييت كاسل.
This move function means you definitely can't explain its exact function, so move is usually used to wrap around the tokens
هذا الفور يعني انتم يعني اكيد مش رح اقدر اشرح كل شغله بالضبط، يعني فور عاديه عم بتلف على التوكنز
Okay? And the condition is that the tokens you're wrapping around must not equal the token that I'm moving.
تمام؟ وشرط انه تكون التوكنز اللي عم بلف عليها ما بتساوي التوكن اللي هلا حركتها انا.
So I have four stones, I moved one, so I'm giving the first to my stones except the one I moved.
يعني هلا انا عندي اربع اربع حجار، فانا حركت واحد، فانا بدي الف على احجاري ما عدا اللي هلا حركته.
Alright? Just to see their positions.
تمام؟ مشان اشوف البوزيشن تبعهم.
If there's a second stone not in the same place as the one I moved, it means a formation has formed for me, so I'm making a formation and adding these two stones with this method.
اذا في حجر ثاني غير الحجر اللي انا هلا حركته بنفس المكان معناتها تشكلت عندي قلعه، فانا بعمل قلعه وبضيف عليها الحجرين بهالتابعه.
And what about the MOV.
طيب هلا تابع الموف.
What is the MOV? We're going to it.
شو تابع الموف؟ بنروح عليه.
Of course, you're telling us to notice that each step is for each class.
طبعا هو انتم بدكم بقول لكم تلاحظوا بكل يعني كل تابع باي كلاس.
Alright? So what does this MOV mean? It means that the stone has passed through all these stages here.
تمام؟ طيب هذا الموف شو معناته قلنا؟ هو عباره عن انه الحجر تجاوز كل هذه المراحل اللي هون.
What does passing mean?
شو يعني تجاوز؟
I won't repeat it, go back to the video and see what it means.
مش رح اعيدهم، ارجعوا انتم بالفيديو وشوفوا شو يعني.
Alright? So focus, when does it start moving?
تمام؟ يعني ركزوا منيح اي متى هو عم بيتحرك.
So that we don't lose again today.
مشان ما يفرشنا بكره.
Well, then, how do we start moving this stone?
طيب، فهو نحن كيف بدنا نحرك هذا الحجر؟
Simply, I gave it the field, which is... what? Which is the value of the die.
بكل بساطه انا اعطيته الستبس اللي هي شو؟ اللي هي قيمه قيمه النرد.
Alright? I gave it the players, we two, and gave it the board.
تمام؟ اعطيته ليست البلايرز اللي هن اثنين واعطيته البورد.
Well, then, how do I move this one?
طيب، طيب انا هلا كيف بدي احركه هذا؟
Alright? I can move it when I want to move it, it was already moving, alright? It was already moving.
تمام؟ بجوز انا وقت بدي احركه هو كان بقلعه، تمام؟ هو كان بقلعه.
So simply, I will get
فانا بكل بساطه
my castles that I have.
بجيب انا الكاسلز اللي عندي.
So, how about we, with the board, can have for example three castles, four castles.
يعني هلا انت نحن بالبورد بجوز يكون عندنا مثلا ثلاث قلاع، اربع قلاع.
For example, two tokens for the human user's castle and two tokens for the computer's castle.
مثلا اثنين ل قلعتين للمستخدم البشري ومثلا قلعتين لل للكمبيوتر.
So we need to respond to the specified castle that I am in.
فنحن بدنا نجيب القلعه المحدده اللي انا هلا فيها.
Alright? How do I know where it is?
تمام؟ كيف بدي اعرف وينها؟
Simply from the tokenization, meaning from the position of the token. I don't know, if I classify a token's meaning, nine times out of ten I go back to the token I'm currently working with.
بكل بساطه من التوكنز يعني او من من البوزيشن الخاص بالتوكن، مش هلا انا بكلاس توكن معناتها تسعه مين عايدي؟ عايدي على التوكن اللي انا هلا عم بشتغل فيه.
I removed the castle.
فجبت القلعه.
Alright? Since I need to move the stone from it, I must remove the stone from it. That is the function remove_token_from_castle.
تمام؟ وكونه بدي احرك الحجر منها فانا لازم اشيل الحجر منها، هي هو التابع ريموف توكن من الكاسل.
Removing the stone from the castle, read the comments many times, they are very clear, meaning honestly, I'm not being lazy.
زائد الحجر من القلعه، اقروا التعليقات كثير واضحه، يعني يعني شات صراحه مش عم بيقصر.
Then I determined its position based on the steps, which is the value of the die roll.
بعدين حددت الموقع تبعه بناء على الستبس اللي هي قلنا قيمه النرد.
And here we did a small check that if the new position of the number's position is above the maximum position we set, then we don't do anything, we just leave it at the maximum position we set, don't change anything.
وهون عملنا تشيك صغيره انه اذا البوزيشن الجديد تبع الرقم تبع عفوا الحجر صار فوق الماكس بوزيشن اللي قلنا نحن بنفرضه فنحن خلص ما تعمل شيء غير تخليه بالماكس ماكس بوزيشن، ما تغير شيء.
Alright?
تمام؟
Okay, we can set the conditions to two, meaning these two conditions are repeated, right? They are repeated.
هون عاد هون يا جماعه يمكن في شرطين، يعني هذول الشرطين مكررين، تمام؟ مكررين.
Scan them at your place.
امسحوهم عندكم.
Right?
تمام؟
Well, in this case, let's see, have we reached the point where we can continue explaining the code?
طيب، بهالحاله يعني مطرح ما نحن هلا صرنا واصلين بالشرح الكود.
The user is now able to play the game perfectly, meaning he can move the pieces.
المستخدم صار قادر انه يلعب باللعبه بشكل مثالي، يعني يحرك الاحجار.
Build castles.
يعمل قلاع.
Attack castles.
يهاجم قلاع.
For example, how does he get out from the starting area, reach the winning stage.
مثلا شو يطلع من منطقه البدايه، يوصل لمرحله الفوز.
Hello, I'm not able to make a run, meaning hello, if he makes a run, maybe the computer will come out and win against him.
هلا انا مش قادر اعمل رن، يعني هلا اذا بعمل رن يمكن رح يطلع الكمبيوتر رح يفوز علي.
Right? But why, meaning he will play according to the algorithm, but it's not 100% working, right? And you have the same thing, it will be.
تمام؟ بس ليك يعني رح يلعب هو بشكل الخوارزميه مش شغاله 100%، تمام؟ وعندكم نفس الشيء رح يكون.
I'm fixing the algorithm called "Khwarizmi," and I'll send you the final code, or maybe by morning we'll see it together.
ف بس صلح الخوارزميه انا وبضبطها ببعث لكم الكود النهائي او يعني يمكن بكره الصبح نحن بنشوفه سوا.
Anyway, regardless of the situation, I'll manipulate the algorithm so that by now we get that specific sign.
وباسوا الاحوال يعني بتحتال على الخوارزميه انا ب يعني بحيث انه نحن بكره نجيب علامه كثير منيحه.
Alright?
تمام؟
After you see them, if there's anything unclear like that, let me know.
بعد ما تشوفوهم اذا في شيء هيك بعده مش واضح قولوا لي.